ANIKET RANA

 $+1(437) \ 331-6725 \diamond \text{Cambridge, ON}$

AniketRana181@gmail.com \$\display https://www.linkedin.com/in/aniketrana \$\display https://github.com/AniketRana

OBJECTIVE

Experienced Software Developer with over 4+ years of experience in finance industry. Working productively in dynamic environments and fluent in C# and JavaScript programming languages used to develop application. Proud team player focused on achieving project objectives in tight deadline with speed and accuracy.

SKILLS

Languages: C#, JavaScript, Python, and C++

Web Technologies: ASP.NET MVC, .NET Core(RazorPages), ReactJS, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Jquery

Databases: SQL Server, MongoDB, PostgreSQL

Other Technologies: WCF, Web API, Microservice, LINQ, Entity Framework, Signal-R, JSON, and XML

Tools: Visual Studio, Visual Studio Code, SSMS, Postman, IIS

Version Control Tools: GitHub, TFS (Team foundation server), BitBucket SDLC Methodology: Waterfall, Agile/Scrum, Kanban, and Iterative

EXPERIENCE

Sr. Software Developer

Jan 2019 - Apr 2021 Surat, Gujarat

Finideas

- Wrote clean, clear and well-tested code for various projects.
- Increased clients satisfaction ratio by implementing Graphs in Fintester
- Improved the client report update efficiency using Signal-R
- Developed back-office portal that managed clients reports based on data using c# and SQL.
- Performed vulnerability patching and investigated and mitigated system weaknesses.

Software Developer

Finideas

Jun 2017 - Dec 2018 Surat, Gujarat

- Built, tested and deployed scalable, highly available and modular software products.
- Achieved 10% growth for BlackBox using web service and API
- Reviewed user requirements, analyzed, designed, implemented installed and delivered training.
- Coordinated deployments of new software, feature updates and fixes.
- Solid troubleshooting, debugging and problem-solving ability.

PROJECTS

BackOffice Build a back-office that mainly focus on mutual fund reports based on the data.

BlackBox This project is mainly focusing on generating the csv trade files based on market condition and sent into the terminal.

Fintester This is backdata testing tool that test the predefine strategy in past data

EDUCATION

Computer Applications Development, Conestoga College, Waterloo Jan 2022 - Aug 2022

Software Quality Assurance and Test Engineering, Conestoga College, Waterloo May 2021 - Dec 2021

Master of Computer Applications, Suresh Gyan Vihar University 2018 - 2020

Bachelor of Computer Applications, SDJ International College 2014 - 2017